<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Shrayas</title>
    <link>https://www.shrayas.com/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Shrayas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Shrayas</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 15:15:39 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.shrayas.com/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Yoga Revisited</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/yoga-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 15:15:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/yoga-revisited/</guid>
      <description>When I started with my training plan, yoga wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly my strong point. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t flow, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even sustain a pose, I never felt like I was doing anything at all. I never felt like I &amp;ldquo;worked out&amp;rdquo;. My coach asked to believe in the practice and to give it my best. And, I continued to try. It&amp;rsquo;s been about a year now that I started this journey and things have changed so much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret of Ultra Running</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/the-secret-of-ultra-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 15:13:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/the-secret-of-ultra-running/</guid>
      <description>The more I get involved with ultra running and more so running in general, the more I get the sense that there is no secret to it. It feels as if asking an ace ultra runner what their secret is, would never get us any real meaningful answer.
Start by making a plan. Then show up everyday, execute the plan and move on with your day. Do it today, do it tomorrow, do it the day after.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Running; The Full Marathon experience</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/on-running-the-fm-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 09:45:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/on-running-the-fm-experience/</guid>
      <description>For context, I&amp;rsquo;ve been running since a good 4 years now.
4 years of putting 1 foot ahead of another. 4 years of braving through pain. 4 years of surviving injuries. 4 years of meeting wonderful people. 4 years of time to reflect. After doing 4 years of running, I thought I had it under my belt. I thought that I had &amp;ldquo;figured out&amp;rdquo; running. After having run so many kilometers with so many people across so many cities and clocking so many hours, I was under the impression that I was &amp;ldquo;comfortable&amp;rdquo; with the sport of running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Running</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/on-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 18:58:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/on-running/</guid>
      <description>Background Circa 2013 - 2014, I was quite the couch potato. Sure I had played a bit of Basket ball in school and got my everyday quota of India&amp;rsquo;s favourite game - gully cricket, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t ever an active person.
That is, until The Himalayas happened.
Soon after my first trek, Raghu and I decided one evening that we&amp;rsquo;d just take a bus to some part of town. Our rendezvous point was about 1 Kilometer from where I stayed at that point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Himalayas</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/the-himalayas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 16:47:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/the-himalayas/</guid>
      <description>In February this year, I visited the holy shrine of Vaishnodevi in Jammu. It is about a 12 KM walk from the base camp - Katra till the holy shrine and I enjoyed that walk more than the darshan itself. The idea of a himalayan trek has been with me for really long but when I looked at the nature surrounding me during that trek, I decided I&amp;rsquo;d go to the Himalayas this year; I decided I&amp;rsquo;d do the trek.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
