<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Shrayas</title>
    <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Shrayas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Shrayas</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 19:29:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.shrayas.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My lack of faith</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/my-lack-of-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 19:29:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/my-lack-of-faith/</guid>
      <description>I am an atheist.
And no, this is not me trying to be “cool” by assuming a label. It is me getting rid of what I believe to be an oppressive power structure, within myself. And writing about it allows me think better about it.
Before I go on any further, I would like to clarify that being an atheist means that I have a lack of belief. Most people assume that I strongly believe that there is no god and that makes atheism a belief system - they are mistaken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your toughest opponent, best friend and strongest competition</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/your-toughest-opponent-best-friend-and-strongest-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/your-toughest-opponent-best-friend-and-strongest-competition/</guid>
      <description>For a very long time, I&amp;rsquo;ve looked for a (ultra) running parallel to this scene:
Which is a scene and something I personally relate to a lot in my life. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen this clip, do so before you come back to read the rest of this
And today, as I was running at 8:00AM in Chennai&amp;rsquo;s sun, I realized. This was in a way, my shadow.
As much as running is regarded as a sport (and an event) where you are running with so many people, fundamentally seasoned runners know that when the buzzer goes off, we are alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick access with SystemTrayMenu</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/quick-access-everything-with-systemtraymenu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 21:34:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/quick-access-everything-with-systemtraymenu/</guid>
      <description>Problem Being head of engineering at a firm means having to juggle a lot of context. And in this quest, I am always looking for ways to optimize my workflow. I can (greatly) simplify all of the work I do into these categories:
Talking to folks &amp;ndash; Zoom Usually via pre defined links - My personal link / Standup link / My founder&amp;rsquo;s personal link My own work &amp;ndash; Visual Studio Open a project in Visual Studio from my local directory of projects Collaboration &amp;ndash; GitHub Open a project in GitHub to log an issue / review a pull request A tool that I already use quite extensively is Key Pirinha which is the Alfred/Spotlight/Launchy equivalent for windows and is blazing fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoga Revisited</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/yoga-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 15:15:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/yoga-revisited/</guid>
      <description>When I started with my training plan, yoga wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly my strong point. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t flow, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even sustain a pose, I never felt like I was doing anything at all. I never felt like I &amp;ldquo;worked out&amp;rdquo;. My coach asked to believe in the practice and to give it my best. And, I continued to try. It&amp;rsquo;s been about a year now that I started this journey and things have changed so much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Secret of Ultra Running</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/the-secret-of-ultra-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 15:13:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/the-secret-of-ultra-running/</guid>
      <description>The more I get involved with ultra running and more so running in general, the more I get the sense that there is no secret to it. It feels as if asking an ace ultra runner what their secret is, would never get us any real meaningful answer.
Start by making a plan. Then show up everyday, execute the plan and move on with your day. Do it today, do it tomorrow, do it the day after.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Running; The Full Marathon experience</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/on-running-the-fm-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 09:45:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/on-running-the-fm-experience/</guid>
      <description>For context, I&amp;rsquo;ve been running since a good 4 years now.
4 years of putting 1 foot ahead of another. 4 years of braving through pain. 4 years of surviving injuries. 4 years of meeting wonderful people. 4 years of time to reflect. After doing 4 years of running, I thought I had it under my belt. I thought that I had &amp;ldquo;figured out&amp;rdquo; running. After having run so many kilometers with so many people across so many cities and clocking so many hours, I was under the impression that I was &amp;ldquo;comfortable&amp;rdquo; with the sport of running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t listen to your body</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/dont-listen-to-your-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/dont-listen-to-your-body/</guid>
      <description>In the quest to become better than the runner you were yesterday, I would argue that it is required of you to not listen to your body.
Allow me to elaborate. The body is a miraculous machine. The very fact that people are able to run such absurd distances is a feat of this very machine. But it is important to, in training, not listen to this very same machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate a quick AWS dashboard using LINQPad</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/generate-a-quick-aws-dashboard-using-linqpad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 22:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/generate-a-quick-aws-dashboard-using-linqpad/</guid>
      <description>Context Logic Soft&amp;rsquo;s mainline product &amp;ndash; WINBDS is an on premise software i.e. we install it at the client location and we support them remotely.
Since a while now,this has been seeing a change. For small installations, usually an instance on the cloud works out cheaper and better. So we&amp;rsquo;ve begun suggesting people to move to AWS when the installation is small enough.
Turns out, if we&amp;rsquo;re diligent about turning the instances off when we don&amp;rsquo;t need them, a windows box on AWS is actually pretty affordable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Express solutions elegantly using your programming language</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/express-solutions-elegantly-using-your-prog-lang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 15:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/express-solutions-elegantly-using-your-prog-lang/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The post features a case study of a real life problem and the C# programming language. It explains how we went about trying to best express the solution within the bounds of the C# language.
Although we use the C# programming language here,the ideas shared in this post aren&amp;rsquo;t specific to it and can be applied to any high level language you are working with.
Problem Recently, for a customer requirement we had to work with a document that has both metadata and data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Running</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/on-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 18:58:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/on-running/</guid>
      <description>Background Circa 2013 - 2014, I was quite the couch potato. Sure I had played a bit of Basket ball in school and got my everyday quota of India&amp;rsquo;s favourite game - gully cricket, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t ever an active person.
That is, until The Himalayas happened.
Soon after my first trek, Raghu and I decided one evening that we&amp;rsquo;d just take a bus to some part of town. Our rendezvous point was about 1 Kilometer from where I stayed at that point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiccups with Hosting ASP .NET 5 apps on Linux (RC1)</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/aspnet5-hosting-hiccups-nginx-kestrel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 20:45:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/aspnet5-hosting-hiccups-nginx-kestrel/</guid>
      <description>Background After the recent dance with multiple Mono versions, the next step was to actually host the application.
Even though the app is largely still unfinished, I wanted to give it a shot on the staging instance to get a feel for things.
The general way to host apps on a Linux box is to have a NGINX reverse proxy in front, listening to different names on port 80 and to proxy the requests to internally running servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP .NET 5, Npgsql, Linux &amp; Mono 4.2</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/asp-net-5-npgsql-linux-mono-4-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 21:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/asp-net-5-npgsql-linux-mono-4-2/</guid>
      <description>Background Logic Soft&amp;rsquo;s primary application is a Windows based application written in C# using Windows.Forms. So when Microsoft announced ASP .NET 5 RC1, needless to say, we were quite excited.
We picked it up and started our experimentation - writing smaller applications and porting some of our side projects to the CoreCLR platform. As long as we didn&amp;rsquo;t go to the place that needed WIN32 APIs, it worked seamlessly.
With a small sum of experience, we took up the task of writing one of our internal dashboards with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic prepared statements in Clojure</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/dynamic-prepared-statements-in-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2015 10:51:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/dynamic-prepared-statements-in-clojure/</guid>
      <description>So just recently, at Logic Soft, we put our first (small) clojure project into production. It was a small library management system that was custom developed for one of our existing clients.
At Logic Soft, we are majorly a .NET house but we&amp;rsquo;re beginning to experiment with different platforms and technologies and felt that this was a small enough project to give clojure a shot (alongside other experiments we conducted with it).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A day with Clojure</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/a-day-with-clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 00:15:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/a-day-with-clojure/</guid>
      <description>It has been a hectic month for me at Logic Soft. I&amp;rsquo;m working on quite a few design related activities for the upcoming book fairs and other internal office work. In doing all of this, most of my programming related activities have been put on hold.
This was ok at first, but then it kind of started getting to me. I really enjoy design but then I find it less satisfying than writing programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Education</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/on-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2014 18:10:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/on-education/</guid>
      <description>Education has always eluded me. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I really enjoy learning, unlearning and relearning. I just think that the &amp;ldquo;education&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve had, didn&amp;rsquo;t teach me this.
I&amp;rsquo;ve never really been a top achiever. I&amp;rsquo;ve never really been the one whose parents could show him off saying he&amp;rsquo;s achieved top grades in class. I&amp;rsquo;ve never really been the one getting into &amp;ldquo;enrichment&amp;rdquo; classes. I&amp;rsquo;ve never been the one who revises before exams; heck I&amp;rsquo;ve never finished studying my portions before the exams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Himalayas</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/the-himalayas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 16:47:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/the-himalayas/</guid>
      <description>In February this year, I visited the holy shrine of Vaishnodevi in Jammu. It is about a 12 KM walk from the base camp - Katra till the holy shrine and I enjoyed that walk more than the darshan itself. The idea of a himalayan trek has been with me for really long but when I looked at the nature surrounding me during that trek, I decided I&amp;rsquo;d go to the Himalayas this year; I decided I&amp;rsquo;d do the trek.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reality, perspective and God -II</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/reality-perspective-and-god-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 14:57:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/reality-perspective-and-god-ii/</guid>
      <description>💡 This post was written long ago and might not necessarily reflect my thoughts at this timeSome people see him in deities. Some people see him as a spiritual being. Some people believe he was a human living among us.
Me, I dont believe in religion. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong. I believe in a god. I believe in a power but I&amp;rsquo;m not a part of those groups that separate this being into different sects demarked by religion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reality, Perspective and.. God</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/reality-perspective-and-god/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 20:03:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/reality-perspective-and-god/</guid>
      <description>💡 This post was written long ago and might not necessarily reflect my thoughts at this timeThe title indicates something very spiritual, but trust me its not. I&amp;rsquo;m not a very spiritual guy and I don&amp;rsquo;t think I will ever be.
These 3 words have meanings associated with them. But today I&amp;rsquo;m going to try and side track you away from what you know of reality, from what you know of perspectives and what you believe in of god and give you my take on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Story, A Moment, A Picture.</title>
      <link>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/story-moment-picture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2012 19:38:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.shrayas.com/posts/story-moment-picture/</guid>
      <description>Its been a really long time since I wrote something.. I guess I lacked that push, I guess I was focussing on other things. But today, I got that push.
7:25PM, was just chilling in my room taking some classes on Natural Language Processing when I got a call &amp;ldquo;Macha, I&amp;rsquo;m in Bangalore, come lets shoot&amp;rdquo;
8:05PM, Brigade Road, I met Waseem. Its been a while since we met and shot together.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
